玛姬
Maggie.
我知道人们在议论纷纷
I know people are saying things --
说关于你和萨沙的好话
nice things about you and Sasha, hmm?
是吗
They are?
是的
They are.
关于那晚
About the other night...
他们觉得是你救了这里
about how they're thinking you saved the place.
别被好话冲昏了头脑
Don't let it go to your head.
那你也别介意
Well, don't let it bother you.
看起来你挺介意的
It seems like it bothers you.
你在上面干什么呢
What you doing up there?
你到底吃不吃
You gonna eat that?
我吃
Yes.
哥们
Dude.
你知道她怀孕了
You know she's pregnant.
逆着毛刮  孩子
Against the grain, kid.
总是逆着毛刮
Always against the grain.
天啊  闻起来真香
Damn, that smells good.
想尝尝吗
Want a taste?
好吧
Okay.
他要的柠檬粉
Here's his damn lemonade.
我厨房里有一些
I had some in my kitchen.
丹妮斯喜欢喝
Denise liked it.
谢谢
Thank you.
回家去
Go home.
交给我吧
Let me take over.
不
No.
我没事
I'm fine.
我答应瑞克照看朱迪思
I told Rick I would watch Judith.
我会做到的
I'm gonna do that.
你该走了
You should go.
我们要坐下了
We're about to sit.
我们还需要一套餐具
We're gonna need another setting.
只有今天一天了  对吧
Today and only today, right?
是的
Yeah.
这些子弹孔
All these bullet holes --
这船很快会进水
this'll take on water quick.
我们也许能到独木舟那
We can probably make it to the canoe.
也许吧
Probably.
如果你想留下来
If you want to stay back...
我要装作你没说那话
I'm going to pretend you didn't just say that.
我决心完成这事
I'm seeing this through.
我们都是
We both are.
我不再等你爸爸了
I'm not waiting for your dad anymore.
我不知道他在哪里
I don't know where the hell he is,
但露西尔
but Lucille...
饿了
...is hungry.
卡尔  把面包卷递给我
Carl, pass the rolls...
麻烦你了
...Please.
《行尸走肉》
瞧瞧
Ohh. Look at that, huh?
就这么容易
Easy as that.
只是个交易
It's just a transaction.
你看起来情况很糟糕
You look like shit,
说明你为之奋斗了
which means you fought for this.
尽到了职责
You did your jobs.
你懂道理  我喜欢
You get it, and I like that.
尼根喜欢
Negan likes that.
听到这话很高兴
That's...good to hear.
你好好干
You play your cards right,
也许我会带你去我们住的地方
maybe I'll show you where we live.
也许我会给你买个三明治
Maybe I'll buy you a sandwich.
告诉我什么时候就好
Just tell me when.
你喜欢看吗  长毛
You like watching, haircut?
是的
Yes.
我是说
I mean...
你该滚远点
You mean to get the hell out of here.
马上
Now!
摩根
Morgan.
这是神之国花园里的
It's just some things from the Kingdom garden --
一些油桃和苹果
some nectarines, some apples.
谢谢  我不需要
Thank you. I am good.
我知道你可以照顾自己
You can fend for yourself, I know,
但新鲜果蔬不是你能随随便便...
but fresh produce isn't something you can just --
真的
Really.
我不需要
I'm good.
以西结吗
Ezekiel?
显然  我说我想一个人待着时
Apparently, some people are having a hard time believing me
有人很难相信我
when I say I just want to be left alone.
我的确是想让你一个人待着  我以后也会的
You know, I was trying to leave you alone, and I will.
但你叫我进来了
But you called me over.
为什么
Why?
你怎么样
How are you?
挺好
Good.
那就好
现在你可以走了
Now you can go.
我觉得你变温柔了
I think you're going soft.
我觉得你要走了
I think you're going.
卡萝尔
Carol, hi.
抱歉打扰你了
I'm sorry to bother you.
摩根  我没想到你也在这里
Morgan, I-I didn't expect you to be here, too.
你来了挺好的
It's good you are.
实际上我想跟你俩聊聊
I wanted to speak to you both, actually.
是关于一件重要的事
It's about something important.
就快到独木舟了
Almost at the canoe.
进水进得太快了
We're taking on water quick, man.
我知道
I know.
瑞克  左边
Rick, on the left!
快到了
We're almost there.
不  不
No, no!
挺住
Hold on!
待在独木舟里
Stay in the canoe!
我可以...
I can -- Just --
亚伦
Aaron!
我没事
I'm okay.
I'm all right.
我没事
I'm okay.
别靠着墙
Stop hugging the wall.
当心
Watch it!
该死的
God damn it!
去把拖把和桶拿来
Go get a mop and another barrel.
我们要留着这鬼东西吗
We're keeping this crap?
我们不需要吃这个
We don't have to eat it.
老天  他超恨泡菜的
Jesus. He hates pickles.
明明有钩子
It's got hooks.
我不知道他为啥不把它系上
I don't know why he didn't strap it in.
和他说了两次了  他个蠢货就是不听
Told him twice. His stupid ass didn't listen.
(恭喜你赢了  但你还是输了)
这是个输不起的
Bit of a sore loser.
看来除了弹药其他东西他都还有剩
Looks like the only thing he ran out of was ammo.
我们得马上把这个弄回去
We got to get this back now.
是啊
Yeah.
他有桨
Well...he's got paddles.
再加上是顺风
And with the wind picking up,
漂回岸边应该不用很久
it shouldn't take long to drift back to shore.
冷静  冷静
Easy. Easy.
我们来弄就好  把这玩意收回去吧
We got it. Take this crap back.
你自己看着点路就行了
How 'bout, this time, you watch where you're going?
行了  别说他了
Oh, come on. Get off his back.
刚刚在那边
You know, back there,
我不是说你做不到
I didn't mean that you couldn't do it.
只是...
It's just...
走了这么远  冒了这么大险
going this far, risking this much
就为了给他们进贡
to get things for them --
很多人并不赞同这种做法
people don't agree with it.
假如你也不情愿的话我是不会怪你的
I wouldn't blame you if you didn't.
我当时也在场
I was there.
我亲眼目睹了一切
I saw what happened on the road.
我们这么做是为了让大家活着
What we're doing is gonna keep people living.
我们必须这么做
We get to do that,
无论我们自身会遭遇什么
it doesn't matter what happens to us.
米恩琼不认同这种活法
Michonne doesn't think this is living.
选择这样的活法
Well, committing to a choice like this,
相比于我们之前的生活...
after living how we did --
自由的...
free --
我理解她
I get it.
是很艰难
It's hard.
这是放弃了除你生命以外的一切
It's giving up everything, right up until your own life.
但只有这样你才能活着
But either your heart's beating, or it isn't.
你爱的人才能活着
Your loved ones' hearts are beating, or they aren't.
我们接受他们的条件
We take what they give us
这样我们才能活下来
so that we can live.
你和尼根在一起多久了
So, how long you been with Negan?
你为什么独自一人在外面
Why were you out there alone?
告诉我
Tell me.
你觉得即便你开口了也改变不了自己的结局
You think talking won't change how this ends for you.
但你不了解我
But you don't know me.
走着瞧吧
Let's see what happens.
我今天不会去杀他
I'm not gonna kill him today.
我要找到一个能让我们取得胜利的方法
I'm gonna find the way that we win.
我要改变自己的结局
I'm gonna change how this ends for me.
这就是我独自一人在外的原因
That's why I'm out here alone.
那是苹果派吗
Is that an apple pie?
你是怎么做到的
Uh. How did you do that?
它还在门外我就闻到了
I could smell it from outside the door.
是你烤的吗
Uh, you baked it?
某个人送给我们以表对我们所作所为的感激
Some guy gave it to us for what we did.
他的小女儿说你应该去竞选山顶寨总统
His little girl said you should run for President of Hilltop.
"支持玛姬当总统"
"Maggie for President."
要碟子吗
Uh, do you want a plate?
不用  这样就行
No, I'm good.
那些是耶稣给你的吗
Did Jesus give you those?
他还在这吗
Is he still around?
趁他还没走  我想在他的单子上加几样东西
There's some things I wanna add to his list before he goes out.
孩子们需要一些写字用的东西
The kids need something to write with --
水笔  铅笔
pens, pencils.
你已经是总统了吗
Are you already president?
我只是和大家聊了一聊
Mm. I've just been talking to people.
耶稣今早离开了
Jesus left this morning.
他让我和你说一声来着  但我忘了
He told me to tell you, but I-I forgot.
好吧  等下次吧
Okay. Next time.
我去拿点牛奶
I'm gonna get some milk.
-让我去吧  -不用  我可以
- Let me. - No, I'm good.
怎么了
What?
耶稣的事你没对玛姬说实话
You're lying to Maggie about Jesus.
为什么这么说
What makes you say that?
有个住在房子里的女孩
A girl who lives in the house.
她给我介绍了所有人
She was telling me about everyone.
他说耶稣是个侦察者
She said Jesus is a runner
他昨天就走了
and that he left yesterday,
不是今早
not this morning.
- 骗她是为她好  - 为什么
- It's for her own good. - Why?
因为我必须做点什么
Because I need to do something,
而她肯定想帮我
and she'll want to help me.
你想杀尼根
You want to kill Negan.
要是你有帮手呢
What if you have help?
要是有帮手  很多人手
If we had help -- a lot of people...
我就不怕告诉她真相
then I wouldn't be afraid to tell her,
因为她知道她不用管
because she'd know it wasn't on her to do it.
-但如果只有我  那么...  -不是只有你
- But if it's just me, then... - ‭It isn't just you.
你和玛姬不是唯一
You and Maggie aren't the only ones
想干掉尼根的人
who want to take Negan out.
-还有...  -不  伊妮德
- There's... - ‭No, Enid.
这样不行
That's not happening.
如果你真关心她
And if you care about her,
就什么都不要说
you don't say anything about this.
我们必须保护她
We have to keep her safe.
你必须保护她
You have to keep her safe.
不是只有你一个人
It isn't just you.
至少看起来只有我
It sure looks like it.
灾变后出现了很多聚居点
A lot of places came together after the world fell apart.
也许你俩都是从某个聚居点过来的
Maybe you're both from one of those places.
这些社区和营地多数都已经消失了
Most of those communities and camps are gone now.
我失去了很多人
I lost people.
我几乎对人们失去希望了
I pretty much lost hope in people.
但后来我找到了神之国
But then I found the Kingdom.
见到了以西结
I met Ezekiel.
看到了他建立的一切
I saw what he built.
但现在我认为他建立的王国受到了威胁
But now I believe what he built is under threat.
-救世军  -救世军
- The Saviors. - The Saviors.
几个月前
A few months back,
以西结和几个护卫在林子里遇到他们一队人
Ezekiel and a few guards met a group of them in the woods.
救世军承认以西结的能力
The Saviors recognized Ezekiel's capabilities,
以西结也不想跟他们打
and Ezekiel didn't want to fight,
所以他们定了个协议
so they cut a deal.
以食物和补给品
In exchange for food and supplies,
换取他们不伤人
no one would get hurt,
不踏入神之国一步
and they'd never set foot inside the Kingdom,
这事知道的人很少
and very few of us even know.
这跟我有什么关系
What does any of this have to do with me?
我知道以西结欣赏你
I know Ezekiel likes you.
也知道以西结信任你
I also know that Ezekiel trusts you,
所以我才来这里
and that's why I'm here.
我需要你们帮我说服他
I need you to help me convince him of something.
现在  我们跟救世军保持着和平
Right now, we have peace with the Saviors,
但早晚会出事
but sooner or later, sometimes's gonna go wrong.
也许是某次贡品少了
Maybe we'll be light on a drop,
也许是我们的人不小心冒犯了他们
or maybe one of ours will look at one of theirs the wrong way,
或者他们干脆决定不再遵守协定
or maybe they'll just decide to stop honoring the deal.
总会出事的
Things will go bad.
一旦出事
And when they do...
神之国就完了
...the Kingdom will fall.
我有过家人
I had a family.
灾变夺走了他们
I lost it to this world.
我目睹了家人死去
I saw them die.
我怕如果我们现在不做些什么
I'm scared that, if we don't do something now,
我们不只会失去更多人  我们还会失去一切
that we won't only lose more people -- we'll lose everything.
我了解救世军  知道他们的所作所为
I know what the Saviors are, and I know what they do.
更知道他们不值得信任
And I know they cannot be trusted.
我猜你们也知道这点
And I think you know that, too.
你想让我们做些什么
What exactly are you asking?
我想让你们帮我劝以西结
I'm asking you to help convince Ezekiel
对救世军先下手为强
to attack the Saviors, to strike first...
灭掉他们
and destroy them.
是为自己准备的吗
Is that for you...
还是尼根
or Negan?
尼根
It's for him.
你要怎么做
How will you do it?
我要扣下扳机
I'll pull the trigger.
他们会杀了你
They'll kill you.
只要他先死就行
As long as he goes first.
你为什么非要送死
Why do you have to die?
因为他必须死
Because he has to.
我赞同
I agree.
但是
But...
为什么你要陪他死
Why do you?
你...
There's, uh...
可以完全对我坦白
No need to lie to me if...
如果这是我们最后一次谈话
this is our last conversation.
如果亚伯拉罕还活着  我们就能战斗
If Abraham was alive, we could fight.
如果格伦还活着
If Glenn was,
玛姬的孩子就有父亲
Maggie's kid would have a father.
米琼恩和卡尔可以战斗
Michonne and Carl can fight.
他们有瑞克
They have Rick.
亚伦有埃里克
Aaron has Eric.
尤金知识丰富
Eugene knows things.
达里尔很强
Daryl's strong.
萨沙呢
What about Sasha?
看着我  罗西塔
Look at me, Rosita.
不该是你去死
It shouldn't have been you.
谁都不该去死
It shouldn't have been anyone.
我们会胜利的
We'll win,
但我们要等待合适的时机
but we need to wait for the right moment
或是大家一起...
or create it...
创造时机
together.
你是我们以后抗争的一员
And you're a part of that together.
不要这么做
Don't do this.
我们需要你
We need you.
听着  我知道他们人很多
Look. I know there's a lot of them.
我猜比神之国的人还多很多
I'm guessing a good deal more than we have at the Kingdom.
出其不意是我们的唯一希望了
The element of surprise is our only hope.
我们得先出击
We need to attack first,
趁着我们还有优势  现在就行动
and we need to do it now while we still have the advantage.
卡萝尔  我估计那种暴力和争斗
Carol, I imagine that violence and fighting
你并没有经历过
is something you haven't been a part of.
你错了
You're wrong.
你大错特错
You're very wrong.
她可能是这屋子里最强的战士
She's probably the most capable fighter in this room.
那就是时候反抗了
Then it's time to fight.
不
No.
我不想参与这事
This is something I am not a part of.
那你就不用战斗
Then you don't have to fight.
你只用说服以西结
You just have to convince Ezekiel
带领神之国反抗
to bring the Kingdom to fight.
你没懂我意思
You're not understanding me.
我不想要你
I didn't want you.
我不想要以西结或是摩根来这
I didn't want Ezekiel or Morgan coming here.
你们的死活与我没有任何关系
And I don't want anything to do with your lives or your deaths.
我只是想一个人待着
I just want to be left alone.
人们会死  很多人会死
People will die -- a lot of them.
你杀过一个人
You killed a man.
我杀人是为了救人
I took a life to save a life.
有什么该死的区别
It's the same goddamn thing.
我们杀他们也是为了自救
We'll be taking their lives to save ours!
只是你不知道能不能成功
Only you don't know that it will.
总有一天你会选择杀人的  摩根
You're gonna choose to kill one day, Morgan,
因为早晚会到那一步的
'cause it will get that bad!
何不现在就做出选择呢
Why not choose now,
在失去你关心的人之前
before you lose someone you care about?
现在是和平的
There's a peace now.
我不想去改变它
I won't be a part of changing that.
也许我们可以促进和平
And maybe we can build on that.
不是和这些人
Not with these people!
当他们反咬一口的时候  他们一定会的
When they turn on us -- and they will --
你们的双手将沾满鲜血
that blood is gonna be on your hands!
但也许你们俩早就习惯了
But maybe you're both used to that.
你也该走了
You should go, too.
是该走了
I should.
我不希望任何人来这了
I don't want anyone else coming around
也不希望别人知道我在这里
or even knowing where I am.
如果你遇到我们认识的人
If you somehow see anyone we know,
告诉他们我不见了
tell them I'm gone.
请你帮我这个忙
Do that for me please.
我从来没想让你看到我
Never meant for you to see me.
你好
Hi.
(禁止野营)
去赴约吗
Hot date?
他们对我印象不错
I'm on a good momentum with them.
我要利用这点
Gonna try to use that.
是吗  怎么做
Yeah? How?
试图靠近他们
By trying to get closer,
即便只是刚开始
even just to start trying.
如果我能做到  一段时间后
If I can do that, after a while --
也许几个月  也许几年
maybe months, maybe years --
之后也许会有转机
maybe then we try something.
我认为我妈就会这么做
I think it's what my mom would have done,
所以我也要这么做
so it's what I'm gonna do.
好的
Okay.
不管之前那是什么
Whatever it was...
我以为我们曾有过美好的感情
I thought we had something good --
至少是美好感情的开始
at least, the beginning of something good.
你为什么要结束它
Why'd you end it?
那又为什么要开始呢
Why'd you even start it?
我当时想忘记一些事
I was trying not to think about shit.
你很可爱  个子又高
You're cute, tall.
有时候挺温柔的
You're sweet sometimes.
所以我利用了你
So I used you.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你待会来吃晚餐吗
Would you be up for dinner later?
只是吃晚餐
I really mean just dinner.
没别的意思
‭No strings.
好的
All right.
怎么回事
What the hell?
一切都好  我发誓
It's cool, I swear.
哥们  你可以从后门走
Buddy, you can walk right out that back gate there,
我什么都不会说的
and I won't say anything to anybody.
我本该在那里的
I'm supposed to be there now,
但听着  我只是想活下去
but, listen, I'm -- I'm just trying to get by,
像你一样
just like you.
求你了
Please.
达里尔
Daryl.
才不是只想活下去
It ain't just about gettin' by here.
而是想得到一切
It's about gettin' it all.
我拿到钥匙了  走吧
I got the key. Let's go.
不  我只是想跟他说说话
No, ‭I just want to talk to him.
我说了不行
I said "No."
别无礼  阿拉特
Dot be an asshole, Arat.
让他过来
Let the man pass.
该死  这是给我的吗
Oh, crap. Is that for me?
我们还没正式见过面
We haven't officially met.
我叫斯宾塞·门罗
I'm Spencer Monroe.
你好
Hi.
尼根就在那
That's Negan.
他在那下面吗
Is he down there?
是的
Yeah.
我们都是尼根
We're all Negan.
不管你想做什么  都行不通
Whatever you're trying to do, you can't.
但你还是有选择的
But you still have some choices.
回家
Go home.
烧了这辆车  沉进湖里
Burn this car, roll it down into a lake,
让它消失
make it disappear.
贮物箱里有个消声器
There's a silencer in the glove compartment.
他在哪
Where is he?
尼根吗
Negan?
在你屋里  混蛋
He's in your house, asshole,
等你呢
waiting for you.
就这样进去吗
Just like that?
我们等了你好几个小时了
See, we've been waiting for hours
就想看看你能交给我们什么
just to see what you gonna bring us, huh?
不如我们先看看吧
Why don't we have a look first?
自来水  空调
Running water, air conditioning,
还有乔迁贺礼
a housewarming gift?
就这么定了
That settles it.
我要在这里搞个度假屋
I am getting myself a vacation home here.
为此干杯
Cheers to that.
这酒不错
Oh, that is good.
你看  就差一张台球桌了
You know, the only thing missing is a pool table.
没有比一场精彩的八球比赛更棒的了
Nothing better than a good game of 8 ball.
街对面那栋房子的车库里有一张
The house across the street has one in the garage.
斯宾塞
Oh, Spencer,
你是我新的好朋友了
you may just be my new best friend.
今天天气这么好
Such a nice day, though --
还窝在车库里
too nice to be cooped up
可不合适  你觉得呢
inside some garage, don't you think?
没错
Yeah.
我有一个更棒的主意
Oh, I got a better idea.
还不错
Not bad.
我们走了很远
We had to go out pretty far.
这他妈是什么
What the hell's this?
恭喜你赢了  但你还是输了
"Congrats for winning. But you still lose"?
你给我们留了封小情书吗
You leave us a little love note?
不是  我只是
No, I just --
我是说  我们不会这样做的  显然不会
I mean -- We wouldn't, obviously --
等等  你说什么
Wait. What?
你刚才是说这是显然的吗
Did you just say it's obvious?
字条不是我们留的
We didn't do that.
我说的不是这张该死的字条
It's not about the damn note!
别过来
Don't.
去见尼根  瑞克
Run along to Negan, Rick.
但是你这位朋友
But your friend here --
他没有地方可去
he's got no place to be.
-你  -后退
- You -- - ‭Back up!
我不可能和瑞克玩这个
I could never do this with Rick.
他只会站在那  皱着眉
He would just be standing there, scowling,
用讨厌的眼神斜视我
giving me that annoying side-eye he gives me.
其实这才是我来找你的原因
That's actually what I came to see you about.
我想和你说说瑞克
I want to talk to you about Rick.
好吧
All right.
说吧  斯宾塞
Talk to me, Spencer.
和我说说瑞克
Talk to me about Rick.
我明白你想要在这做什么
I get what you're trying to do here,
你想建造什么
what you're trying to build.
我并不是说我赞同你的方法
I'm not saying I agree with your methods,
但我懂了
but I get it.
你在搭建网络
You're building a network.
让大家为集体做贡献
You're making people contribute for the greater good.
有道理
It makes sense.
但你应该知道瑞克·格兰姆斯
But you should know that Rick Grimes
以前就不能很好的和他人共事
has a history of not working well with others.
是吗
Is that so?
这里原来不是瑞克管事
Rick wasn't the original leader here.
是我妈妈
My mom was.
她当时做得很好
She was doing a really good job of it.
瑞克出现后不久  她就死了
Then she died, not long after Rick showed up --
我兄弟也死了  我爸爸也死了
same with my brother, same with my dad.
这么说  这些年这里一直欢乐美满
So, everything was peachy here for -- what -- years?
瑞克出现后  突然之间你就成了孤儿
And then Rick shows up, and suddenly, you're an orphan?
这是我听过的最悲惨的故事
That is the saddest story I've ever heard.
-好在他不再管事了  -这不重要
- Good thing for you ‭he's not in charge anymore. - Doesn't matter.
他自负得无法控制
His ego's out of control.
他总能找到办法搞砸事情
He'll find a way to screw things up,
按他自己的想法行事  接管一切
to try and do things his way, to take over.
他就是这么对我妈妈的
That's what he did with my mom.
他还会重蹈覆辙的
That's what he'll do again.
那么你到底想怎么做呢
What exactly are you proposing be done about that?
我是我妈妈的儿子
I am my mother's son.
我可以成为像她一样的领导者
I can be the leader she was.
这正是这个地方需要的
That's what this place needs.
也是你需要的
That's what you need.
所以我应该让你管事
So I should put you in charge
你是这个意思吗
that's what you're saying?
那样对我们都更好
We'd be much better off.
你没事  你没事
You're all right. You're all right.
好了  好了
All right, all right, all right.
让他学会教训了
Point made.
我的心还在跳  对吧
My heart's still beating, right?
其实  斯宾塞  我在考虑
You know, I'm thinking, Spencer.
我想到瑞克之前威胁要杀了我
I'm thinking how Rick threatened to kill me,
以及他显然恨我入骨
how he clearly hates my guts.
但他现在在外面
But he is out there right now,
替我搜集物资  以确保
gathering shit for me to make sure
我不会杀了任何住在这里的好人
I don't hurt any of the fine people that live here.
他把仇恨都咽进肚子里了
He is swallowing his hate
真正替我办了事
and getting shit done.
那是需要勇气的
That takes guts.
再看看你
And then there's you...
等着瑞克走了
the guy who waited for Rick to be gone
鬼鬼祟祟跑过来找我谈
so he could sneak over and talk to me
想要借我的刀杀人
to get me to do his dirty work,
好取代瑞克的位置
so he could take Rick's place.
所以我不得不问问
So I got to ask --
如果你想取代瑞克
if you wanna take over,
何不自己动手杀了他  然后取而代之呢
why not just kill Rick yourself and just take over?
什么  不  不是
What? No, no.
我没有  我不是那个...
I didn't -- I don't --
你知道我是怎么想的吗
You know what I'm thinking?
我大概猜到了
'Cause I have a guess.
因为你没胆
It's because you got no guts.
真尴尬
How embarrassing.
竟然有呢
There they are.
你的胆子一直在你的身体里
They were inside you the whole time.
你是有胆的
You did have guts.
这是我这辈子错得最离谱的一次了
I've never been so wrong in my whole life!
快过来个人  把血污都清理干净
Now, someone oughta get up here and clean this mess up.
有人想接替他打完这一局吗
Anyone want to finish the game?
来吧
C'mon.
有人吗
Anybody?
来嘛
C'mon.
我都快赢了
I was winning!
妈的
Shit!
去他妈的
What the shit?!
该死的  你想杀了老子吗
Shit! You just -- You tried to kill me?!
-你打中了露西尔  -她碍事了
- You shot Lucille! - She got in the way.
这是什么
What is this?
这玩意儿是手工做出来的吗
This little bad boy made from scratch?
瞧瞧这折痕
Look at those crimps.
这是手工做的
This was homemade.
你或许很愚蠢  亲爱的
You may be stupid, darlin',
但是你显示出非凡的创造力
but you showed some real ingenuity here.
阿拉特
Arat,
把刀移到那姑娘的脸上去
move that knife up out on that girl's face.
露西尔美丽光滑的脸庞
Lucille's beautiful, smooth surface
再也不会想以前那样了
is never gonna look the same,
凭什么你的脸可以美丽光滑
so why should yours?!
除非
Unless...
除非你告诉我这是谁做的
Unless you tell me who made this.
是我
It was me.
我做的
I made it.
我觉得你在撒谎
You see, now I just think you're lying.
你到了现在还敢对我撒谎
And you lying to me now?!
真遗憾
Such a shame.
阿拉特只能割花你美丽的小脸蛋了
Arat's gonna have to cut up that pretty face.
再答一次
One more try.
是我做的
It was me.
你可真硬气啊
You are such a badass!
好吧
Fine.
就顺了你的意吧
Have it your way.
阿拉特
Arat...
杀个人
Kill somebody.
不要  是我做的
No. It was me!
不要
No!
-我们达成了协议的  -瑞克
- We had an agreement. - Rick!
大家瞧啊  瑞克来了
Look, everybody, it's Rick.
你的人逼我这么吼来吼去的  嗓子都哑了
Ah, your people are making me lose my voice doin' all this yelling.
瑞克  对我说句谢谢怎么样
Rick... how about a "Thank you"?
虽然我们这段关系的初始
I mean, look, I know we started this relationship
是我敲烂了你朋友们的脑袋
with me beating the holy shit out of your friends,
因此我们永远不可能友好地坐下来
and because of that, we're never gonna sit around
给对方编辫子
and braid each other's hair
或是互相倾吐内心最深处最黑暗的秘密
or share our deepest, darkest secrets,
但你能不能有点感恩之心
but how about a little credit?
我苦心孤诣地向你展示  我是个多么讲道理的人
I just bent over backwards to show you how reasonable I am.
你的孩子
Your kid --
他藏在我的一辆卡车里
he hid in one of my trucks
用冲锋枪扫倒了我的一堆手下
and machine-gunned a bunch of my men down,
我还把他安全带回来了
and I brought him home, safe and sound,
给他做了意面吃
and I fed him spaghetti.
另一个你的人
Another one of your people --
他想要我杀了你  让他取而代之
well, he wanted me to kill you and put him in charge.
我为你...干掉了他
I took him out...for you.
另一个人  这位
And another one, here --
她击中了露西尔  刚才想杀我
she shot Lucille, trying to kill me just now,
所以我又帮你减少了一张要养活的嘴
so I gave you one less mouth to feed.
瞧瞧她那样儿
And by looking at her --
那张嘴可吃了不少
that mouth did some major damage.
个人来说
Now, personally,
我不会选择杀她
I wouldn't have picked her to be the one to go,
但是阿拉特
but Arat --
我不知道  不太信任她
I don't know -- didn't trust her.
你的东西在大门那里放着
Your shit's waiting for you at the gate.
快走吧
Just go.
当然可以  瑞克
Sure thing, Rick...
在我找出造这颗子弹的
right after I find the guy or gal
男人或女人之后
that made this bullet.
阿拉特
Arat?
是我
It was me!
不  不是
No, it wasn't.
是我
It was me.
只有我
It was only me.
你
You?
需要空弹壳  四孔转动装弹器
It required one spent casing, one four-holed turret reloader,
火药  火药漏斗
powder, one funnel for the powder --
闭嘴
Shut up.
我相信你
I believe you.
露西尔  给我力量
Lucille, give me strength.
我要带走你的子弹制造者  瑞克
I'm gonna be relieving you of your bullet maker, Rick --
以及你在前门给我留下的东西
that and whatever you left for me at the front gate.
不管你搜集到了多少东西  都不够
And however much you scavenged, it's not good enough,
因为在今天的事后
because you're still in
你仍然处在深深的
a serious, serious hole
无底洞中
after today.
我们出发
Let's move out!
不不不
No! No, no!
求你了  只带走我吧
Please, just take me!
不
No!
瑞克  我不会撒谎
Rick, I ain't gonna lie --
你的厨房一团糟
your kitchen is a goddamn mess.
下次见
I'll see you next time.
卡尔告诉我你在这里
Carl told me you were in here. I...
我找到了我想找的东西
I found what I was looking for.
我之前想跟你和亚伦一起去
I wanted to go with you and Aaron,
但我做不到
but I couldn't.
我必须找到自己的路
I had to go my way.
当我找到时
But when I found it...
我发现
...I realized that...
我不希望那只是我的路
I didn't want it to be my way.
我希望那是我们的  我和你的路
I wanted it to be ours -- me and you.
他们有更多人  比我们想的还多
There are more of them, even more than we thought.
敌众我寡  相去甚远
We are outnumbered. It's not even close.
但这不能改变我的想法
But that doesn't change the way that I feel,
因为这不会改变事实
because it doesn't change the way that things are.
我们依然活着  瑞克
We're still alive, Rick.
发生了那么多事
So much has happened,
那么多我们本不可能挺过去的事
so much that we shouldn't have lived through.
而
And...
不管与此无关还是正因为如此
and in spite of it or maybe because of it,
我们都活下来了
we did.
我们还在这里  我们俩
We're still here, the two of us.
我们还活着  而且我们会继续活下去
We're still standing, and we're gonna keep standing.
所以我们该对此做些什么呢
So, what do we do with that?
我们如何让活着更有意义呢
How do we make that mean something?
我们是能做成事的人
We're the ones who get things done.
这是你说的
You said that.
我们是能活下去的人
We're the ones who live.
所以我们更需要战斗
That's why we have to fight --
不是为了我们
not for us,
是为了朱迪思  为了卡尔
but for Judith, for Carl,
为了亚历山大  为了山顶寨
for Alexandria, for the Hilltop --
为了所有人
for all of us.
我们能抗争他们  瑞克
We can fight them, Rick.
我们能找到战胜他们的方法
We can find a way to beat them.
我们能做到
We can do this.
但是
But...
只有
Only if...
我们一起做
we do this.
是的  我现在知道了
Yeah, I know that now.
我现在知道了
I know that now.
萨沙  伊妮德
Sasha! Enid!
- 你没事吧  - 我没事
- You're okay?  - I'm okay.
孩子没事
The baby's okay --
我们都没事
all of us.
你说得对
You were right...
从一开始就是对的
right from the start.
你告诉我们要准备抗争
You told us to get ready to fight.
我没有听  我听不进去
I didn't listen, and I couldn't.
现在我能了
I can now.